陪审团 ，就以这一点...
And on that point, members of the jury...
我的报告到此为止
I rest my case.
万达，你好
Hello, Wanda.
<font  color="#4096d1">片名：笨贼一箩筐
- 肯，你好 - 你好，万达
- Hi, Ken. - Hello, Wanda.
肯，这是奥图
Ken, this is Otto.
你好，肯，万达常提起你的
Hello, Ken. Wanda's told me a lot about you.
很棒的鱼
Hey, great fish!
加一点柠檬水，酸泡菜调味酱 棒极了
A little squeeze of lemon, some tartar sauce, perfect.
乔治回来了没有？
George back yet?
没有，他要去...
No, he had to go to--
什么？
What?
你口吃的相当厉害，肯
That's quite a stutter you've got there, Ken.
我不介意
It doesn't bother me.
乔治需要懂得用武器的人？
So George needs a weapons man, eh?
肯，要茶吗？
A cup of tea, Ken?
他会想要的
Yeah, he'd like one.
我在中央情报局的一位朋友 也有口吃
I had a good friend in the C.I.A. had a stutter.
这要了他的命，可恶
It cost him his life, damn it.
乔治，你好
Hi, George.
乔治，你好，你要威士忌吗？
Hello, George. Get you a scotch?
好的
Yeah.
这是奥图
This is Otto.
- 你是万达的哥哥 - 乔治，我很高兴来到这里
- You're Wanda's brother. - It's good to be here, George.
英国是个很好的国家
England is a fine country.
她告诉了你我们需要什么吗？
She tell you what we need?
类似这些？
Something like that?
类似这些
Something like that.
温迪，你好
Hello, Wendy.
今天怎样？
Had a good day?
我整个早上都在 叫垃圾处理人员来这里
I spent the morning trying to get the waste disposal man to come...
我和玛杰莉布克吃午饭 她不断地埋怨丈夫
have lunch with Majorie Brooks who complained about her husband...
然后我和菲利帕玩游戏
then I had to play three rubbers with Philippa Hunter...
然后我回来这里 桑特森送错花了
and I come back here and Sanderson's have sent the wrong flowers.
哎呀，真糟糕
Oh, no.
- 你想喝茶吗？ - 好的
- Would you like some tea? - Yes.
我赢了官司
I won the case.
我现在才拥有一些私人时刻
This is the first moment I've had to myself all day.
你好，波席亚，表演怎样？
Hello, Portia. How was the show?
很糟，爸爸，我需要一匹新马
Awful, Daddy. I need a new horse.
- 我以为你喜欢“魅影” - 它不适合我
- I thought you liked Phantom. - He's not fit for dog meat.
我可以换掉它吗？ 很重要的，而且不需要很多钱
Can I change him please, Dad? It's vital and won't cost much.
- 我们要问贝琳达 - 我以为你在泡茶
- We ought to ask Belinda. - I thought you were making tea.
- 我是，对不起 - 我去弄吧
- I am, darling. Sorry. - Suppose I'd better get it.
- 让我来 - 不，让我来
- Let me do it, please. - No, I'll do it.
- 我赢了官司 - 这个裂了
- I won the case. - Now this is cracked.
它们每个值十万元 总共有135个
They're worth about 1 00,000 each. There are 1 35 of them.
也就是一千三百万
That makes 1 3 million, my friends.
- 美金还是英镑？ - 是英镑
- Dollars or pounds? - Pounds, pet.
这是大买卖
This is the big one.
好
Okay.
对
Yeah.
- 奥图？ - 什么事？
- Otto? - Yes?
行吗？
Okay?
- 什么？ - 计划
- What? - The plan.
对，没问题
Yeah, great. No problem.
关于应付警方方面怎样？
What was the middle thing about the police?
我们周二在希思罗机场会合
We don't meet up at Heathrow until Tuesday--
- 对 - 我还没说完
- Oh, yeah. - I haven't finished yet.
因为警方会监视所有机场...
Because the police will watch all the airports...
持续72小时监视
for 72 hours.
我知道
I know.
你想不想我...
You want me to...
找一辆大汽车...
get a big...
准备作逃亡之用？
car for the getaway?
肯，找来一辆轿车，好吗？
Yes, Ken. A limo, okay?
在上面挂上外交车牌，好吗？
And put diplomatic plates on it, right?
如他在抢劫期间要说话怎办？
What if he has to say something during the break-in?
没有人会在抢劫期间说话
Nobody says anything during the break-in, Otto.
奥图 ，没关系，肯没问题的
It's okay, Otto. Ken's good.
那么下周...
So, next week...
我们不用找工作
we won't have to look for work...
它也不用找我们
and it won't have to look for us.
奥斯卡怀尔德
Oscar Wilde.
肯，你很喜欢动物吧？
You really like animals, don't you, Ken?
它们有什么吸引你？
What's the attraction?
因为你能够信任它们
Because you can trust them...
它们不会...
and they don't sh--
- 在你身上撒尿？ - 不会经常炫耀
- Shit on you? - Show off all the time.
你知道尼采怎样形容它们吗？
You know what Nietzsche said about them?
他说它们是天主的第二个错误
He said they were God's second blunder.
再见，妹妹
Bye, sis.
你帮我告诉他...
Well, you tell him from me...
我可以给你看...
that I could show you--
乔治，再见
Bye, George.
如果你见到母亲，替我问候她
If you talk to Mom, tell her I said hi.
- 不要让他碰你 - 再过一天我们就能在一起了
- Don't let him touch you. - One more day, we're together.
我为我的哥哥道歉 我知道他很麻木不仁
I'm sorry about my brother. I know he's insensitive.
他的生活很苦，爸爸以前常打他
He's had a hard life. Dad used to beat him up.
好
Good.
不许动，否则你们死定了
Anybody moves, and you're dead!
笨蛋，小心走路
Look where you're going, chauvinist pig.
这里的人以为他们拥有行人道
Really, people here just think they own the pavement.
真有趣，我喜欢抢劫英国人
That was fun. I love robbing the English.
他们很有礼貌
They're so polite.
- 肯，什么事？ - 那条狗
- What is it, Ken? - The dog.
我们没有撞到那条狗
We didn't hit the dog.
这关乎二千万元 他竟然担心一条虫
Twenty million dollars, he's worried about an insect.
- 这不是... - 你的口吃没有改善
- It's not an in-- - Stutter's not getting any better.
- 你有没有想过做手术？ - 住口
- Have you thought about surgery? - Shut up.
再见
Bye.
- 我们分道扬镳吧 - 周二在希思罗机场见
- Let's split. - Meet you at Heathrow on Tuesday.
低调点，不准庆祝
Lie low. No celebrating.
不准庆祝？
No celebrating?
- 两小时后见 - 好，再见
- See you in a couple of hours. - Okay. Bye.
- 为二千万元干杯 - 为大功告成干杯
- To 20 million. - To a job well done.
为我们干杯
To us.
继罗密欧与茱丽叶后...
To the best brother and sister team since--
最佳的兄妹队伍干杯？好极了
Romeo and Juliet? Yeah.
你相信那些蠢才信了我们吗？ 真是笨蛋！
Do you believe those Cockney klutzes bought our story? What morons!
- 我想告诉你一件事 - 什么事？
- I want you to know something. - What?
就算你是我的哥哥 我仍然想和你上床
Even if you were my brother, I'd still want to fuck you.
打电话
Make the call.
不准说意大利话
No Italian!
奥图 ，打电话
Make the call, Otto.
你真的是意大利人吗？
Are you really Italian?
我叫奥图 ， “八” 的意思 说“乔治，再见”吧
My name is Otto. It means ''eight.'' Say ''Arrivederci a Georgio. ''
- 乔治，再见 - 可以帮我接警局吗？
- Good-bye, George. - Can you put me through to the police?
你好，抱歉打扰你
Yes, hello. Sorry to trouble you.
你们应该有兴趣知道 哈顿花园的抢劫
I thought it might interest you to know the Hatton Garden robbery...
是由一位乔治汤玛森先生策划的
was pulled off by a Mr. George Thomason...
他住在西伦敦
who lives at Flat Three...
梅利路基普利公寓
Kipling Mansions, Murray Road...
三号
London West Nine.
警察，开门
Police. Open up.
开门
Come on. Open up.
开门，否则我们会撞开这道门
Open the door, or we'll knock it down.
乔治法兰西汤玛森
George Francis Thomason.
护照？机票？
Passport? Tickets?
钱
Money.
混蛋
Asshole!
- 万达，我们很有钱 - 对
- We're rich, Wanda. - Yup.
和我在一起过去这两个礼拜 是你生命里最刺激的时刻
Bet these last weeks with me were the most exciting weeks of your life.
你说得对
You said it.
好
Okay.
真失望！
Disappointed!
混蛋
Son of a bitch!
你这辈子要做什么 才会令人相信你？
What do you have to do in this life to make people trust you?
住口
Shut up.
- 人们总是利用我 - 住口然后想想吧
- People always take advantage of me. - Shut up and think.
他把它移到哪里？
Where has he moved it?
- 你在做什么？ - 我在思考
- What are you doing? - I'm thinking.
我在想我要怎样对付他
I'm thinking of what I'm going to do to him.
首先我会用琴线勒死他 你去哪里？
First I'll hang him up with piano wire. Where are you going?
我去和他谈谈
I'm going to talk to him.
跟谁谈？
Talk to who?
在你为父母安装窗门期间
In the course of installing these windows for your parents...
你跪在破碎窗户地上的 玻璃碎片上
you knelt on the floor where there was broken glass from a dropped pane.
对
That's right.
你的父母可以证实吗？
Your mother and father can confirm this?
可以 还有他的婶婶乔治亚汤玛森
Yes, and his aunt, Georgina Thomason.
巴勒，是的？
Good, Bartlett. Yes?
抱歉打扰你，有位小姐来见你
Sorry to interrupt you, sir. Thomason, young lady to see you.
- 还有什么事？ - 暂时没有
- Anything else? - That's everything for the moment.
- 你不用赶着离开吗？ - 不用
- You don't have to dash off? - No, absolutely not.
乔治，肯买了鱼食
George, Ken's got the fish food.
- 他晚点回来 - 谢谢你
- He'll be in later. - Thanks.
- 利奇先生，你认为怎样？ - 玻璃的事没问题
- What do you think, Mr. Leach? - We may be all right with the glass.
他们还会做什么？
What else are they gonna come up with?
我的天，我不相信会发生这种事
Oh, my God. I can't believe this is happening.
小姐，这里不容许这样
That's not allowed in here, miss.
- 你有没有事？ - 我没事
- Are you okay? - I'm all right.
乔治，我认为我不能应付
George, I don't think I can handle this.
昨晚我害怕得不能入睡 我以为警察会来
I was so afraid to sleep last night. I thought the police were coming.
别提了 ，好吗？
Leave it out, okay?
听着...
Listen, listen.
你在我那里住
You stayed at my place.
我们很晚才睡，你弄早饭给我吃
We slept late. You made me breakfast.
什么？
What?
他在这里做什么？
What's he doing here?
他想见你
He wanted to see you.
乔治，是谁做的？凯文迪兰尼？
Who did it, George? Kevin Delaney?
你想我干掉他吗？ 你想我做什么就说吧
You want me to rub him out? Anything. You name it.
- 我有朋友帮我查探 - 好
- I have friends making inquiries. - Good.
珠宝很安全
The jewels are very safe.
如果我被捕 我会归还所有珠宝来减轻刑期
If I get sent down, it all gets handed back to cut my sentence.
为了再减少刑期...
Now, to cut my sentence even more...
我可以告诉他们谁是我的搭档
I could tell them who done it with me...
如果我有任何事不满意的话
if I wasn't very happy about everything.
你刚才说什么？
What was the middle thing?
滚开
Piss off.
- 你想不想我... - 马上
- Do you want me to-- - Now.
- 你不认为... - 你认为吗？
- You don't think-- - Do you?
- 乔治？ - 什么？
- George? - What?
你肯定车库安全吗？
Are you sure the garage is very safe?
相信我
Trust me.
谢谢你
Thank you very much.
谢谢你，再见
Thanks a lot. Bye. Have a good day.
- 那又怎样？ - 他不肯定是你
- So? - He's not sure it was you.
- 那样不错 - 你又怎样？
- That's something, I guess. - What about you?
他相信我，所以他对你不肯定
He believes me. That's why he can't figure out about you.
- 他对什么不肯定？ - 他不肯定是否你供出他，笨蛋
- Figure out what? - If you turned him in or not, stupid.
千万...
Don't...
不要...
ever, ever...
叫我笨蛋，知道吗？
call me stupid, okay?
什么？
What?
那是乔治的律师
That's George's lawyer.
另一个一定是大律师
The other guy must be the barrister.
- 那又怎样？ - 相信我
- So? - Trust me.
若发生什么意料之外的事 记得通知我
You let me know if anything unexpected turns up.
对不起
Excuse me.
我是不是认识你的？
Don't I recognize you?
应该不认识
No, I don't think so.
但你是有名的大律师吧？
But you are a famous barrister, aren't you?
不算是
Well, hardly.
可不可以帮我签名？
Could I have your autograph anyway?
- 当然可以 - 谢谢你
- Yes, certainly. - Thanks.
我在研究你们的法制
I'm studying aspects of your legal system.
- 我是美国人 - 真的？
- I'm American. - Oh, really?
我只是刚开始研究 我觉得很有趣
I've only just started, though. It's fascinating.
你为什么来这里？
What brings you here?
说起来会令人有点尴尬
It's a little embarrassing.
我有一位朋友
I have a friend.
我明白了 ，好了
Oh, I see. Well, there you are.
我早就知道！你是阿奇利许！
I knew it! You're Archie Leash!
- 利奇 - 对
- Leach. - Right.
两周前我在法庭上见过你
I saw you in court two weeks ago.
- 赌场被劫事件？ - 你很棒
- The casino break-in? - You were great!
- 我... - 我很仰慕你
- Well. - I'm a big fan of yours.
我喜欢你的盘问技巧
I love the way you cross-examine.
我真的很佩服你
I really admire your work.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我不会再打扰你 - 我不...没关系
- I'd better not keep you. - I don't suppose you-- Fine. Right.
好
Well.
谢谢你，我会很珍惜
Thank you for this. I'll treasure it.
你也会说法文
You speak French too.
发生什么事？
What's going on?
不管乔治决定做什么 他会先告诉利奇
Whatever George decides to do, he's going to tell Leach first.
- 为什么？ - 因为他是乔治的律师
- Why? - 'Cause he's his lawyer.
- 我知道 - 我会去认识利奇先生
- Yeah, I know that. - So I'm gonna get to know Mr. Leach.
因为乔治会告诉他钻石在哪里
'Cause George is gonna tell him where the diamonds are.
那是我要查出的事
That's what I'm gonna find out.
你做得很好
You've done well, my son.
我们要把它藏在哪里？
Now, where are we going to hide it?
很好，不要告诉万达
Very good. Don't tell Wanda anything.
奥图或许会问她
Otto might get something out of her.
乔治，你会没事吧？
George, you are gonna get off?
对，肯，不用担心，我们会处理
Sure, don't worry about it, Ken. We'll fix it.
对奥图有什么发现吗？
Now, anything on Otto?
- 还没有 - 你监视着他
- Not yet. - You watch him.
没问题
It's okay.
看来警察们搜查过所有东西
Looks like the police have been all over it.
让我先更衣，然后我帮你找
Let me just change clothes, then I'll help you look.
你好，肯的宠物
Hello, Ken's pets.
英国鱼，醒来！
Wake up, limey fish!
你怎样去认识这个律师？
So, how are you gonna get friendly with this lawyer?
我不知道，我会随机应变
I don't know. I'll improvise.
可恶的昆虫！
Fucking insects!
从他们说话的态度来看 我以为英国人不喜欢女人
I thought Englishmen didn't like women, the way they talk.
他很直接，他其实蛮可爱
He's straight. He's kind of cute, in a pompous sort of way.
你喜欢他吗？
You got the hots for him?
我没有恋尸癖，谢谢
I'm not into necrophilia. Thanks.
这是什么一回事？ 突然变了 “引诱英国人周”吗？
What is this? Hump-a-limey week, suddenly?
奥图不喜欢，他或许会妒忌
Otto doesn't approve. Otto might get jealous.
说出来吧！
Oh, speak it!
对
Yeah.
奥图 ，不要在这里
No, not here, Otto.
Not here, Otto.
<font  color="#4096d1">不，不要在这里
No, not here,
<font  color="#4096d1">奥图 ，不！
Otto. No,
万达，看我有什么
Look what I've got, Wanda.
宝藏
A treasure.
我的天，是肯，我以为又是警方
Oh, my God, Ken, it's you. I thought it was the police again.
乔治还真可怜呢？ 噢，肯
Isn't it horrible about George? Oh, Ken!
肯，我头痛 你可以帮我买些阿斯匹灵吗？
I have such a bad headache. Could you run and get me some aspirin?
- 糟了 - 那是什么？
- Shit. - What's that?
我哥哥在浴室里
That's my brother. He's in the bathroom.
我们刚见过乔治，实在好可怕
We just saw George. Oh, it was horrible, Ken.
真的很可怕
Just horrible.
乔治很可怜吧？
Isn't it terrible about George?
如果让我找到那个告密者...
When I find the bastard who squealed--
我喜欢他！
I love that man!
你在做什么？
What are you doing here?
我在做什么？
What am I doing here?
万达很不高兴 她需要和家人谈谈
Wanda was upset, Ken. She needed to talk to family.
她刚洗完澡
She's just had a shower.
我要和你谈谈
I've got to speak to you.
- 你现在没事吧？ - 我没事，谢谢你来
- Are you okay now? - I'm fine. Thanks for coming.
- 需要我就打电话给我 - 好，谢谢你
- Call me if you need me again. - Okay. Thanks.
你怎么了？ 你不能考虑她的感受吗？
What's the matter with you? Can't you think about her feelings?
- 事情很可疑 - 糟了
- There's something funny going on. - Oh, dear.
你连自己为什么兴奋也不知道 是吗？
You don't even know why you're excited, do you?
我不想乔治在场时说话
I didn't want to say anything while George was around.
你是时候面对现实了吧？
Isn't it time you faced up to certain realities?
你是个很有吸引力的男人
Come on. You're a very attractive man.
你很聪明，有很棒的骨架
You're smart, you've got wonderful bones...
很漂亮的眼睛，衣着有趣
great eyes and you dress really interestingly.
我们一起一定会很高兴 就是你跟我
We could have a lot of fun together, you and I.
我们会很适合对方 你认为怎样？
We'd be really good for each other. What do you say?
你一定是在说笑...
You must be jo--
- 肯，我可以吻你吗？ - 不可以
- May I kiss you, Ken? - No, you fucking can't!
只是轻轻一吻 但不是湿吻
Just a peck. No tongue. Ken!
你不知道我是同性恋
You didn't realize I was gay.
对不起
Okay, look, I'm sorry.
我处理得很糟
I've handled this badly.
肉体可以等待
Look, the physical side can wait.
你需要时间
You need time.
你会考虑吗？
Will you think about it?
我的天
Oh, my God.
肯，有人打过电话来
Ken, somebody just called!
他们说警方知道赃货 在福汉的一个车库里
They said the police know the loot is in a garage in Fulham somewhere.
我们要立即去拿它
You and I have to go get it right now.
我们要比警方先一步找出地点
You and I have to go before the police find out where it is.
- 什么？ - 没事
- What? - It's all right.
什么？
What?
乔治
George.
移走了它
Moved.
- 乔治移走了赃货？ - 对
- George moved the loot? - Yes.
肯，他移去了哪里？
Where did he move it, Ken?
我不知道，有钥匙 但不知道用来开什么
I don't know where it is. There's a key. I don't know what it's for.
是在...
It's in the--
不要告诉我 你还是不要告诉我
Don't tell me. It's better that you don't tell me.
如果不是为了乔治
Oh, you know, if it wasn't for George.
奥图...
Otto...
尝试吻我
tried to kiss me.
我认为他或许会
I thought he might.
什么都没有，没有痕迹
No. Nothing. No marks at all.
- 但这是保险箱钥匙吧？ - 对
- But it is a safety deposit box key? - Oh, yes.
但英国有数以百万计的保险箱
But it could be any one in England. There are millions of them.
饭店、银行、办公室...对不起
Hotels, banks, offices. Sorry.
谢谢你
Thank you.
可恶
Fuck.
警官，就是他
That's him, Inspector.
是他想谋杀我的狗儿们
He's the one who tried to murder my dogs.
大卫森？
Davidson?
有位美国法律学生想和我谈谈
There's an American legal student here who wants to see me for a moment.
- 约翰爵士什么时候来？ - 十二点半
- What time's Sir John due? - Half past 1 2:00, sir.
进来
Come in.
- 你好 - 幸会
- Hi. - How very nice to see you.
- 我有打扰你吗？ - 当然不是
- Am I interrupting? - Absolutely not.
- 真的？ - 真的，很高兴能和你见面
- Really? - Really. Delighted to see you.
你好
Hello.
就是这里？
So, this is the place, huh?
- 对 - 很不错
- This is it. - Very nice.
今早我去过法庭 实在很引人入胜
I was over at the courts this morning. Boy, it's fascinating.
- 我可以学到很多东西 - 你喜欢吗？
- Really so much to know. - You like it?
大家都戴这个，你也戴吗？
Everybody wears these. Do you wear one?
荒谬
Ridiculous.
我只有几分钟时间...对不起
Well, I only have a few minutes before-- Sorry.
- 对不起 - 我现在洗耳恭听
- I'm sorry. - Till then I'm all yours, as they say.
我只有几个问题
I just have a couple of questions.
我对于初步刑事程序...
I'm having a little problem understanding...
- 不大明白 - 很好
- preliminary criminal procedures. - Good.
什么是监听会？
What exactly is the committal?
很有趣
Ah, interesting.
基本上是初步调查
Basically, it's a preliminary investigation...
控方提出初步证据
where the prosecution presents prima facie evidence...
证明有足够证据向被告提出起诉
that the accused has a case to answer for trial.
书本是那样写的
That's what the books say.
例如我的朋友乔治汤玛森
Let's just take, for example, my friend George Thomason.
- 对 - 当他被...
- Right. - When he goes into his committal--
- 汤玛森？ - 对
- Thomason? - Yes.
你认识他吗？
Do you know him?
- 我在为他辩护 - 你在说什么？
- I'm defending him. - What are you talking about?
我是他的代表律师
I'm his barrister, his lawyer.
真棒
That's so great.
真古怪，你觉得很古怪吧？
That's so weird. Isn't that weird?
我很高兴你帮他辩护
I'm so happy it's you that's defending him.
谢谢
Thank you.
他一定能够脱罪
He's sure to get off now.
难以置信
Wow.
- 我现在可以看你工作 - 谢谢
- I could watch you work now. - Please.
真了不起
Amazing.
乔治会在监听会...
Anyway, at the committal, George would then plead--
- 不认罪 - 真的？
- Not guilty. - Really?
他们的证据大部分是间接证据
Oh, you see, the evidence against him is largely circumstantial.
但是有目击证人吧？
But there was an identification, wasn't there?
但那是一个老妇人 我认为他们抓错人
True, but a very elderly lady. I think they've got the wrong man.
你认为不是他做的
You don't think he did it.
为了讨论，假设你认为是他做的
Let's just say, for argument's sake, that you did think he did it.
如果还有对他不利的证据
If further evidence against him came to light, for example.
你会建议他认罪
You would then advise him to plead guilty...
归还珠宝以求减刑
and turn over the jewels to get his sentence cut.
他会把珠宝交给谁？你？
And he would turn them over to who? To you?
- 理论上可以这样说 - 当然
- Theoretically? - Oh, of course.
这样...
Well, uh--
抱歉我忘了你的名字
I'm so sorry. I've forgotten your name.
万达，真棒...真的有三个...
Wonderful, wonderful. Wanda, there were really three--
- 你不是万达格肖维吧？ - 我是
- Not Wanda Gershwitz? - Yes.
我的天
Oh, my God.
- 什么事？ - 你是他的不在场证据
- What? - You're his alibi.
- 我不能和你谈 - 为什么？
- I can't talk to you. - Why not?
小姐，你是辩方证人
My dear young lady, you are a defense witness.
我要立即请你离开，对不起
I must ask you to leave immediately. I'm so sorry.
我说过什么？
What did I say?
- 和证人谈话是不合道德的 - 在美国是可以的
- It's not ethical to talk to a witness. - Everybody does it in America.
在英国是绝对禁止这样做
Well, not in England. It's strictly forbidden.
我要坚持这样 否则我要放弃这宗案件
I must insist, otherwise I may have to give up the case.
对不起，请离开？
I'm sorry. Please?
我今天不是来谈刑事程序
I didn't come here today to talk about boring criminal procedures.
你是知道的
Come on. You know.
我进来的那一刻你已经知道
You knew the minute I walked in here.
我要你
I want you.
什么？
What?
- 约翰爵士来了 - 请他进来
- SirJohn is here. - Show him in, please.
- 我想和你上床 - 什么？
- I want you to make love with me. - Pardon?
没什么
Nothing.
- 阿奇，你会和我上床吗？ - 不会，抱歉
- Will you take me to bed, Archie? - No. Sorry.
再见，叔叔
Bye, Uncle.
他不会认罪
He's pleading not guilty...
审讯前你很安全
so you're safe until the trial.
利奇认为不是他做的
Leach doesn't think he did it.
肯说有一把保险箱钥匙 但只有乔治知道在哪里
Ken says there's a safe deposit box key, but only George knows where it is.
万达，谢谢你
Thank you, Wanda.
- 你有什么发现？ - 没什么
- What have you found out? - Not a lot.
- 你知道他明天会上法庭？ - 我知道
- You realize he's in court tomorrow? - I know that!
没有发现吗？
So nothing, huh?
没有
Nix.
零
Zip.
毫无头绪
Diddly. Bupkes.
- 太大了 - 不是
- Oh, it's too big. - No, it isn't, Portia.
- 很巨大 - 不是
- It is enormous. - No, it isn't.
- 母亲，求求你 - 不是
- Please, Mother. - No, absolutely not.
我那么可怜但你却不在乎
I'm so miserable, and you just don't care.
波席亚，住口
Do shut up, Portia.
每天都有人向我埋怨
All I get all day is people complaining to me.
亲爱的
Oh, dear.
阿奇，我想你和她谈谈整容手术
Archie, I want you to speak to her about plastic surgery.
希望你会听我说 我想你和波席亚谈谈
I do wish you'd listen to me. I want you to speak to Portia.
好，我早上会找她谈谈
Right. I'll have a word with her in the morning.
阿奇，晚安
Good night, Archie.
万达，晚安
Good night, Wanda.
- 你向谁说晚安？ - 对不起
- Good night, who? - Sorry, darling.
只是关于明天一些 笨案件的老太婆
Just some stupid case I've got tomorrow with some lousy old hag.
你是梅利路基普利公寓的...
Are you George Francis Thomason...
乔治法兰西汤玛森吗？
of Kipling Mansions, Murray Avenue, London W9?
是
Yes, sir.
你被控持械行劫 汤玛森先生，坐下
The charge is one of armed robbery. Sit down, Mr. Thomason.
普西维先生 你准备好今天的监听会吗？
Are we ready for a committal today, Mr. Percival?
准备好，会用法例第62条例
Yes, it will be under Section 62, Madam.
对...62
That is correct-- 62.
这是所有证供
Here are the statements, all to be fully bound, please.
汤玛森先生，站起来
Stand up, Mr. Thomason.
你会在中央刑事法庭受审
You are hereby committed to stand trial at the Central Criminal Court.
本案件有点紧急
There is some urgency about this case, Madam...
本案主要证人伊莲科迪女士 年纪老迈...
as the main witness, Mrs. Eileen Coady, is elderly...
她最近的心脏有问题
and has had serious heart difficulties recently.
本案件有可能...
Is there any possibility that this case...
提早审讯吗？
might be put down for an early trial?
那是排期官的责任
That would be for the listing officer at the Old Bailey.
请带他去监狱
Take him down to the cells, please.
是
Yes, sir.
来吧
Come along, now.
你在做什么？你很漂亮
Hi, hon. How are you doing? Ooh, you look great.
我喜欢你的发型 你有时间喝咖啡吗？
I love your hair. Do you have time for a coffee?
- 不，我要走了 - 你有想过吗？
- No, I've got to go. - Have you thought about it though?
他为什么给你这个？ “比西街69号伊莲科迪”
One thing: Why did he give you this? ''Eileen Coady, 69 Basil Street''?
他想你怎样做？送花给她？
What does he want you to do, send her flowers?
帮她去购物？令她快乐？
Do her shopping? Show her a good time?
谋杀她？
Rub her out?
他想你谋杀她？
He wants you to rub her out?
他会杀她
He's going to kill her!
走开，否则我会杀掉你
Fuck off, or I'll kill you.
讨厌的英国人！
Limey fruits!
肯，老妇人会遇上意外？
So the old lady's going to meet with an accident, Ken?
- 是什么那么有趣？ - 没什么
- What's so funny? - Nothing.
我觉得杀死老妇人不是很好
It's just that wasting old ladies isn't nice.
总比鸡奸好
Well, it's better than buggering people.
我和你打赌一镑你不会杀她
I'll bet you a pound you don't kill her.
- 好 - 好
- All right. - All right.
我喜欢看你走路时的屁股
I love watching your ass when you walk.
很漂亮，不是吗？
Is that beautiful, or what?
不要走近他！他属于我的！
Don't go near him! He's mine!
我打赌一镑你不会杀她
A pound says you won't kill her.
- 你什么时候能处理？ - 周四不行
- When could you look at it? - Well, Thursday's hopeless.
周五我太太会去看歌剧
My wife's going to the opera Friday evening.
到时我可以来看看 周六早上我打电话给你
I could have a look at it then, call you at the office Saturday morning.
谢谢你
I'd really appreciate that. Thanks, Archie.
我知道我们不该谈话 打电话给我吧
I know we're not allowed to talk. Give me a call.
我不能够
I can't.
求求你
Please?
- 我们不能谈话 - 我们不需要讲话
- We're not allowed to speak. - We don't have to.
我不想听你说话
I don't want you for your conversation.
我很想，但...
I'd love to, but--
- 发生什么事？ - 我周五有约会
- What happened? - Got a date Friday.
你可以不发出那种声音吗？
Look here, do you mind not making that terrible noise?
我的狗儿们要睡午觉
My dogs will be having their nap.
很棒的狗儿
Nice doggy.
奥图 ，你在做什么？
Otto, what are you doing?
这是佛教冥想技术 能够集中你的攻击力
It's a Buddhist meditation technique. It focuses your aggression.
和尚在打仗前会这样做
The monks used to do it before they went into battle.
奥图 ，那是什么佛教？
What kind of Buddhism is this, Otto?
混蛋！
Asshole!
- 这是早期密宗冥想... - 这是什么？
It's an early Tantric medita-- What is this?
为了取得资料 我或许和他做朋友
In order to get information, I might have to get friendly with him.
我们终于准备好了
Well, we're ready now, at last.
- 欣赏歌剧吧 - 你的晚饭在冰箱里
- Good. Enjoy the opera, darling. - Your supper's in the fridge.
- 很好，谢谢 - 做个好孩子
- Marvelous. Thank you so much. - Be good.
你说好朋友是什么意思？
When you say ''friendly,'' what are we talking about here?
诚挚？礼貌？支持？什么？
Cordial? Courteous? Supportive? What?
我不知道，看看到时怎样
I don't know. Let's just see what happens.
朋友或许包括...
So, friendly might include...
真正的上床，不是吗？
actual, what, penetration, would you say?
- 你不要妒忌 - 妒忌？
- I don't need your jealousy now. -Jealousy?
- 对 - 我只是好奇
- Yes. - Hey, I'm merely curious.
我妒忌那个花花公子？
Me, jealous of that fop?
- 我的奶子又怎样？ - 他可以触摸它们吗？
- What about my tits? - Does he get to handle them?
我预计会那样
Yes, that's my forecast. I'll stand by that.
- 用鼻子擦？ - 我认为为了二千万元是值得的
- Nuzzling? - I think $20 million is worth nuzzling.
- 机会是百分之八十 - 吸吮呢？
- Eighty percent chance there. - Sucking?
- 我以为你不是妒忌 - 我不是，我不相信妒忌心
- I thought you weren't jealous. - I'm not. I don't believe in jealousy.
那是弱者的行为
It's for the weak.
只要你碰他的那话儿 他就死定了
One thing, though: touch his dick, and he's dead.
我叫你爸爸拿汽车去维修
I told your father to get the car serviced.
- 我们会去吗？ - 住口 ，波席亚
- Aren't we going, then? - Do shut up, Portia.
快点
Hurry up.
你蔑视我吗？
Do you despise me?
我不会那样说
No, that's not a word that leaps to mind.
我可以留下来吗？
Can I stay, then?
当然可以，看
Of course. Look.
- 万达... - 我知道
- Wanda-- - I know.
你太太回来了
Your wife's coming back.
不是她，她不会这么快回来
No, it's not her. She'll be gone for hours.
是关于我向你说过的说话
It's about what I said to you.
我们是可以交谈的
It is all right for us to speak.
- 是吗？ - 只要我们不讨论案件
- It is? - Provided we don't discuss the case.
好的
Oh, fine.
但如果有人看见我们交谈...
It's just that if anyone saw us talking--
他们不会
But they won't.
抱歉我那么傲慢
Sorry if I seem pompous.
阿奇，你是最棒的
Oh, you're the best, Archie.
等一下，我很口渴
Not yet. I'm thirsty.
你要喝什么？
What shall I get you?
威士忌
Whiskey.
你是我这一生...
You are the sexiest, most beautiful girl...
所见过最性感...
I have ever seen...
最美丽的女子
in my entire life.
把酒给我
Get me my drink.
那么...
So...
如果乔治决定改变他的计划...
if George decides to change his plea...
他会告诉你赃货在哪里吧？
he'd tell you where the loot is first, wouldn't he?
我们不能讨论审讯，知道吗？
Darling, we mustn't talk about the trial, okay?
我知道 我只是在说理论上是那样
I know. I just meant theoretically.
吻我那里
Kiss me there.
理论上
Oh, theoretically.
如果被告想改为认罪...
Well, if the defendant wants to change his plea...
根据他向代表律师的指示...
in his instructions to his legal representative...
正常程序...
the normal procedure--
- 什么事？ - 阿奇，很棒
- What's the matter? - It's wonderful, Archie.
- 什么事？ - 你令我欲火焚身
- What's the matter? - You're getting me so hot.
- 对不起 - 我要喝些饮料
- Sorry. - I need something to drink.
一些冰的饮料，冰箱有吗？
Something cold, maybe in the fridge?
- 香槟？ - 我最喜欢的
- Champagne? - My favorite.
别走开
Don't go away.
- 你在这里做什么？ - 轻松点
- What are you doing here? - Relax.
- 滚开 - 我听到呻吟声，我很担心
- Get the fuck out of here. - I heard moaning. I was worried.
我在假装，笨蛋
I was faking it, you stupid jerk.
不要再叫我笨蛋，我没有妒忌
Don't ever call me stupid, and I'm not jealous.
- 那就离开 - 好
- Then leave. - Okay.
这里很棒
It's a nice place.
不要碰他的那话儿
Don't touch his dick.
他的太太
His wife.
天啊，去睡觉吧
Now, for goodness' sake, get off to bed.
没有冰块了
Oh, God, there isn't any ice.
香槟
Champagne.
什么事？
What's the matter?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
香槟，欢迎你回家
Champagne, dear, to welcome you home.
让我倒一杯给你
Let me pour you a glass.
那是谁的汽车？
Whose is the car?
- 汽车？ - 在车道上那一辆
- The car? - Blocking the drive.
你回来了 ，看到你真高兴
There you are, dear. Cheers. Nice to see you.
歌剧怎样？提早结束吗？
How was the opera? Finished early?
那是谁的汽车？
Whose car is it?
是我的，很漂亮吧？
Mine. It's a beauty, isn't it?
阿奇，我把酒放在哪里？
Where did I leave my drink, Archie?
这是谁？
Who is this?
- 你不知道吗？ - 利奇太太，你好吗？
- Don't you know? - How do you do, Mrs. Leach?
我是哈里曼佛圣约翰
I'm Harvey Manfredin St.John.
- 我隶属中央情报局 - 中央情报局？
- I'm with the C.I.A. - C.I.A.?
对，太太
That's correct, ma'am.
我在想上你们美丽的厕所前
I was just telling your husband here...
告诉你的丈夫...
before I had to go to your beautiful bathroom...
我们在附近的房子里
we've got a high-ranking K.G.B. defector...
有一位苏联国家安全委员会 变节者
in a safe house near here.
我们正在向他盘问
We're debriefing him as of now...
我们在检查...
and we're just checking...
附近所有房屋
all the houses in the neighborhood.
- 为什么？ - 苏联国家安全委员会
- For what? - For K.G.B.
- 有危险吗？ - 没有
- Is there any danger? - No, no.
现在没有
Not now.
我们...
We--
我们只是想通知大家
We just want to keep everyone informed.
阿奇，谢谢你的酒
So, Archie, thanks for the drink.
抱歉打扰你们，我要离开了
Sorry to have troubled you, folks. I'll see myself out.
- 通知大家？ - 太太，不用担心
- Keep everyone informed? - So there's no panic, ma'am.
- 但这不是秘密吗？ - 你不知道有多秘密
- But isn't it a secret? - You have no idea how secret.
你为什么告诉大家？
Why are you telling everyone?
这是烟幕？
It's a smoke screen?
- 什么？ - 虚张声势
- What? - Double bluff.
你不知道情报工作是怎样
You obviously don't know anything about intelligence work, lady.
这是XK红色27号技术
It's an XK Red 2 7 technique.
我父亲是情报人员
My father was in the Secret Service, Mr. Manfredin St.John.
我很清楚当你在盘问一个 苏联国家安全委员会成员时...
I know perfectly well that you don't keep the general public informed...
你们是不会通知公众的
when you are debriefing K.G.B. defectors in a safe house.
是吗？
You don't, huh?
除非你是疯了或很笨
Not unless you're congenitally insane or irretrievably stupid.
- 不要说我笨 - 为什么？
- Don't call me stupid. - Why on earth not?
你们英国人觉得自己很优越吧？
You English are so superior, aren't you?
你想知道如没有美国保护你们...
Would you like to know where you'd be without us...
你们会变成怎样吗？
the old U.S. of A., to protect you?
你们只会成为俄罗斯帝国的 一个小县罢了 ！
The smallest fucking province in the Russian empire, that's what!
女士，不要说我笨 你只用感谢我
So don't call me stupid, lady. Just thank me.
谢谢你进来保护我们
Well, thank you for popping in and protecting us.
如果不是我们 你们现在会说德语
If it wasn't for us, you'd all be speaking German, singing--
那是我的哥哥帮我掩护
That's my brother covering for me.
摆脱你的太太，去拿我的项链
Get rid of your wife and get my necklace.
对，我会想办法摆脱她
Necklace, right. I'll think of something to get rid of her.
- 你在和谁说话？ - 我自己
- Who are you talking to? - Myself, darling.
- 那是什么叫声？ - 我朋友的哥哥
- Who was that shouting? - The brother of a friend of mine.
- 阿奇，究竟是谁？ - 我不知道
- Archie, who on earth? - I don't know.
真有趣，他按门铃，我打开门
Extraordinary. He rang the bell, I opened the door.
- 我需要饮料 - 我们去酒吧
- I need a drink. - Let's go to the pub.
- 什么？ - 我们去酒吧
- What? - Let's go to the pub.
- 波席亚，你想来吗？ - 我们15年来没有去过了
- Would you like to come, Portia? - We haven't been there in 1 5 years.
现在应该让波席亚见识一下
It would be nice for Portia to see it now.
阿奇，你不是认真的吧？
Honestly, Archie.
- 究竟发生什么事？ - 我以为画快要掉下来
- What on earth is the matter? - I thought the picture was falling.
- 镇静点 - 现在安全了
- Pull yourself together. - It's all right. It's secure now.
这是什么？
What's this?
谢谢，你会来吗？
Thanks, Portia. Well done. Coming with us?
- 那是什么？ - 项链
- What was that? - A kind of necklace.
- 发生什么事？ - 没什么，来吧
- What's going on? - Nothing, dear. Let's go.
- 我可以看看吗？ - 什么？
- Can I see that? - What?
你的手
In your hand.
你的另一只手
Your other hand.
- 波席亚，去你的房间 - 我们会去酒吧吗？
- Portia, go to your room. - Are we going to the pub?
我可以解释 我在办公室遗留了一些文件
I can explain. I left some papers at the office.
他们派了一个新女职员来
Now! And they sent a new girl up.
- 阿奇 - 真的，她是加拿大人
- Oh, Archie. - Really, she's Canadian.
- 她说今天是她的生日 - 很漂亮，谢谢你
- She mentioned it was her birthday. - It's lovely. Thank you.
甚至刻有W字母
It's even got a ''W'' for Wendy.
我很高兴你喜欢
Oh, I'm so glad you like it, darling.
这是你送给我最漂亮的礼物
It's the most beautiful thing you've ever given me.
这不像你
This isn't like you.
- 你疯了吗？ - 我救了你一命
- Are you fucking crazy? - Hey, I saved your ass.
我差点哄到他，混蛋！
I had him right where I wanted him, you asshole!
奥图 ，我有工作给你做
I give you one fucking thing to do, Otto.
你应该载我来这里，闭嘴
You're supposed to drive me here. Shut up!
放松
Oh, relax.
等一下，找你的
Hold on. It's for you.
现在不行
Not at the moment, no.
我不肯定我什么时候能够
Yes, I'm not quite sure when I'll be able to get hold of that.
好，谢谢你，对，尽快
Yes, I do appreciate that. Yes, as soon as possible.
那样很好
Well, that would be very nice, obviously.
我们很快又会再见吧？
So see you soon, I hope?
再见
Bye, Frank.
玛吉，放松
Easy, Maggie.
冷静下来
Calm down.
Easy, girl. Easy.
过来
Come here.
玛吉，嗅嗅吧
Smell, Maggie, smell.
现在
Now.
杀！
Kill!
我们现在把它入土为安
We therefore commit its body to the ground...
尘归尘
earth to earth, ashes to ashes...
土归土
dust to dust...
希望它会复生
in sure and certain hope of the resurrection...
找到永生
to eternal life.
亲爱的，发生什么事？
Hello, honey. What happened?
- 没什么 - 那是什么？
- Nothing. - What's that?
- 不是祖母吧 - 还没有
- Not Granny? - Not yet.
那是给谁的？
Who's it for, then?
一条鱼、一个法国人 电话接线生
A fish. A Frenchman. A phone operator.
- 是朋友 - 四脚朋友？
- Friend. - A four-legged one?
- 我妹妹在哪里？ - 她在...
- Where's my sister? - She's in the--
- 谢谢 - 洗手间
- Thank you. - Lavatory.
- 有什么事？ - 什么？没什么
- Anything? - What? No.
- 你为什么在这里？ - 我在这里因为我很无聊
- Why are you here? - I'm here because I'm bored.
在这个讨厌的城市闲逛闷死了
Bored wandering around this God-awful city...
移开乔治的丑陋照片...
shoving George's ugly pic--
和一些低层次的英国人谈话
talking to a lot of snotty, stuck-up, intellectually inferior British faggots.
他们很不安
Jesus, they're uptight.
他们在壮年时肌肉就僵硬
They get rigor mortis in the prime of life in this country.
他们就那样呆站着
Standing there with their hair clenched.
等着一周的结束
Counting the seconds till the week ends...
那么他们能打扮漂亮
so they can all dress up like ballerinas and...
然后去玩乐
whip themselves into a frenzy at the flat at 4.
“2B...”
''2B, St.--''
老实说...
To be honest...
我讨厌他们
I hate them.
佯装他们是律师...
I mean, pretending they're so fucking lawyer--
自以为很优越...
so fucking superior...
操着一口假口音
with those phony accents.
肯，我不是说你 你的声音很漂亮
Not you, Ken. You've got a beautiful speaking voice.
当你没有口吃时
When it works.
混蛋！
Son of a bitch!
你想吃午饭吗？
So, wanna have some lunch?
- 他有联络你吗？ - 谁？
- Have you heard from him? - Who?
- 阿奇 - 没有，我要染头发
- Archie. - No, I have to finish my hair!
没有？我走了 你不打算见他吗？
Nothing? I'm out of here! No plans to see him?
再见
Okay. Bye, bro!
万达，再见
Bye, Wanda!
对不起
Oh, sorry.
- 什么？ - 那不是属于他们的
- What? - It wasn't theirs to sell.
一位老妇交给他们刻字 她快八十也快死了
An old lady gave it to them to engrave. She's about 80 and dying.
这个很有纪念价值 有人把它放在展示柜里
It's of great sentimental value. Somebody put it in the display cabinet.
- 那是他们的问题 - 不可以那样说
- That's their problem. - Not really.
- 你付钱买下的 - 他们接受他们的错误
- You paid for it. - They do accept their mistake.
他们想用这个代替它 这个的价值高三倍
They're offering you this to replace it. It's three times as valuable.
这是你给我的礼物之中最棒的
This is the nicest thing you've ever given me, which I absolutely love.
现在你想我交还它 和用这样俗不可耐的东西代替
Now you want me to give it back and replace it with something vulgar.
- 我不想你交还它 - 他们不能拿回去
- I don't want you to give it back. - Well, they can't have it.
告诉他们不能
Tell them they can't have it.
你是律师
You're the bloody barrister!
阿奇，很漂亮
Oh, Archie, it's beautiful.
很漂亮
It's just beautiful.
我的天！你看！
Oh, my God! Look!
阿奇，很漂亮
Oh, Archie, it's beautiful.
很棒吧？
Isn't it wonderful?
- 是谁的？ - 属于办公室的一位同事
- Whose is it? - Belongs to someone at the chambers.
他们在哪里？
And where are they?
去了香港几个星期
Hong Kong. Gone for weeks.
阿奇，很不错的地毯
Nice rug, Archie.
可以吗？
May I?
- 你在做什么？ - 我在跳波尔卡舞
- What are you doing? - The polka, I think.
你令我感到很自由
You make me feel free.
自由？
Free?
你知道身为英国人是怎样吗？
Do you have any idea what it's like being English?
时常都很正确和被压制？
Being so correct all the time? Being so stifled...
时常都害怕做错事？
by this dread of doing the wrong thing?
问人“你是否已婚？”
Of saying to someone, ''Are you married?''
怎料对方说 “太太今早离开了我？”
and hearing, ''My wife left me this morning''?
或问人“你有没有孩子？”
Or saying, ''Do you have children?'' And being told...
对方却说“他们在星期三 都被烧死了”
''They all burned to death on Wednesday.''
万达，你可以看到...
You see, Wanda, we're all...
我们都害怕尴尬
terrified of embarrassment.
所以我们...
That's why we're so...
都那么死寂
dead.
我大部分朋友都很沉闷 就像和死尸共膳一样
Most of my friends are dead. We have these piles of corpses to dinner.
但你充满生气，我也想那样
But you're alive, God bless you, and I want to be.
我厌倦所有事情
I'm so fed up with all this.
我想和你上床
I want to make love with you.
我是个好情人
I'm a good lover. At least...
至少我在十四世纪时是
I used to be, back in the early 1 4th century.
我们可以上床吗？
Can we go to bed?
好
Yeah.
等一下，小心你的头
Hang on. Mind your head.
我认为我爱你
Oh, I think I love you.
- 我可以问你一个问题吗？ - 什么也可以
- Can I ask you a question? - Anything.
我的项链在哪里？
Where's my locket?
- 我拿不到 - 什么？
- I couldn't get it. - What?
温迪不肯交还它 我买了这个给你
Wendy wouldn't give it back. Look, I got you this instead.
- 你喜欢吗？ - 不喜欢
- Like it? - No, Archie.
我要拿回我的项链
I have to have mine.
为什么？
Why?
我母亲临死前...
My mother gave it to me...
给我的
on her deathbed.
对不起
I'm sorry. All right, darling.
- 我会拿回给你 - 你保证吗？
- I'll get it for you. - You promise?
我会想办法
I'll think of something.
跟我不完全信任的人上床
Sex is very difficult for me...
对我来说是很困难
with somebody that I don't trust completely.
我保证我会取回它
I promise I'll get it, okay?
阿奇，我爱你
I love you, Archie!
我对你一见钟情
I've loved you ever since the first second I saw you.
- 那是什么？ - 什么？
- What was that? - What?
你哥哥这次没有带你来吧？
Your brother didn't bring you here this time, did he?
- 没有 - 他不知道？
- No. - He has no idea?
- 他完全不知道 - 什么？
He doesn't have a clue.
What?
- 他很笨 - 真的？
- He is so dumb. - Really?
他以为林肯住在盖底斯堡
He thought the Gettysburg Address was where Lincoln lived.
他讲关于中央情报局的谎话 真是差劲
All those terrible lies he told about the CIA.
很痛苦
So painful.
当他听到你女儿叫波席亚...
And when he heard your daughter's name was Portia...
他问为什么用汽车名字命名
he said, ''Why did they name her after a car?''
我喜欢你笑的样子
I love the way you laugh.
我爱你，你很有趣
I love you. You're funny.
怎么这样聪明的女孩的哥哥 会这么...
How come a girl as bright as you could have a brother who's so--
不要说我笨
Don't call me stupid.
我的天！
Jesus Christ!
- 来吧！ - 很痛
- Come on! - Ouch!
来吧！
Come on!
我稍后应付你
I'll deal with you later.
你对她做了什么？
What have you done with her?
她没事
She's all right.
道歉吧
Now, apologize.
- 什么？ - 道歉
- What? - Apologize.
- 糟了 - 你精神错乱吗？
- Oh, shit! - Are you totally deranged?
你这个自大狂妄
You pompous, stuck-up...
不可一世...
snot-nosed, English...
笨蛋...
giant, twerp...
不知廉耻的混蛋
scumbag, fuck face, dick-head, asshole!
真有趣
How very interesting.
你真的很俗不可耐，不是吗？
You're a true vulgarian, aren't you?
是你俗不可耐，道歉吧
You're the vulgarian, you fuck! Now, apologize!
我向你道歉？
Me to you?
道歉
Apologize.
好，我道歉
All right, I apologize.
- 你真的感到内疚吗？ - 我真的感到抱歉
- You're really sorry? - I'm really, really sorry.
我诚心地道歉
I apologize unreservedly.
- 你真的收回刚才的说话？ - 对
- You take it back? - I do. I offer...
我完全收回我的说话
a complete and utter retraction.
刚才的毁谤毫无根据...
The imputation was totally without basis in fact...
那不是正确的评判 而且动机是...
and was in no way fair comment and was motivated...
敌意，如果我的言语...
purely by malice, and I deeply regret...
为你和你家人 带来不安，深感歉意
any distress that my comments may have caused you or your family.
我承诺将来不会...
And I hereby undertake not to repeat...
再重覆任何这样的行为
any such slander at any time in the future.
好
Okay.
你说你爱他
You said you loved him!
对，你要回答这个选择问题
That's right! Now, here's a multiple choice question for you.
甲 ，万达在说谎
A: Wanda was lying.
乙，万达说的是真相
B: Wanda was telling the truth!
你会选哪一个？
Which one are you gonna pick?
第一个是什么？ 你说不打算见他
What was the first one? You told me you were not planning to see him.
因为我知道你会坏事
Because I knew you'd come along and fuck it up!
我在处理很敏感的事情
I was dealing with something delicate.
我在向一个重要的人下手
I'm setting up a guy who's incredibly important to us--
他会告诉我赃货在哪里...
who's going to tell me where the loot is...
他们或许会来拘捕你 你却像...
and if they're gonna come and arrest you-- and you come loping in...
没穿护身衣的蓝波般闯进来 把他吊在五层楼的窗外
like Rambo without a jockstrap and dangle him out a fifth-floor window.
那样很聪明吗？
Now, was that smart?
- 好 - 很糟吗？
- Okay. - Was it shrewd?
那是很棒还是很笨的策略？
Was it good tactics or was it stupid?
不要说我笨
Don't call me stupid.
说你笨就是侮辱愚蠢的人
Oh, right! To call you stupid would be an insult to stupid people!
我见过比你聪明的羊
I've known sheep that could outwit you.
我穿过智商比你高的裙子
I've worn dresses with higher IQs.
但你自以为是学者吧？猿猴
But you think you're an intellectual, don't you, ape?
猿猴不会看哲学书的
Apes don't read philosophy.
它们会看，只是不明白
Yes, they do. They just don't understand it.
让我向你解释几样事情，好吗？
Now, let me correct you on a couple things, okay?
阿里士多德不是比利时人
Aristotle was not Belgian.
佛教的主旨不是自私
The central message of Buddhism is not ''Every man for himself.''
伦敦地下铁不是政治运动
And the London Underground is not a political movement.
那些全是错的 我查过的
Those are all mistakes. I looked 'em up.
你刚袭击了...
Now, you have just assaulted...
能够令你不用坐牢而且致富的人
the one man who can keep you out of jail and make you rich.
你会怎样做？
So what are you gonna do about it?
学者会怎样做？
What would an intellectual do?
柏拉图会怎样做？
What would Plato do?
- 道歉 - 什么？
- Apologize. - Pardon me?
什么？
What?
- 道歉！ - 对！
- Apologize! - Right!
对不起
I'm sorry.
不是向我道歉，向阿奇道歉
No. Not to me, to Archie.
诚心地道歉，否则我们死定了
And make it good or we're dead.
我非常...
I'm so very, very--
你去见鬼吧！
Fuck you!
我非常...
I'm very, very sss--
非常...
Very, very--
小偷先生，你好，你去哪里？
Hello, Mr. Burglar. Going somewhere?
你以为你可以抢劫利奇先生？ 我会教训你
Thought you could rob Mr. Leach, eh? Well, I'm gonna teach you a lesson.
他是我很好的朋友
He just happens to be a very good friend of mine...
当他发现你将被我抓去警局时...
and he's going to be very pleased with me when he finds you...
他会很高兴
all tied up and ready for the police.
不要叫我奥图 ，我是...
And don't call me Otto. To you, I am Mr.--
我的天！
Oh, my God!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
Please. I'm sorry.
我不知道是你
I didn't know it was you.
我怎会知道是你？
How could I know it was you?
我怎会猜到是你？
I mean, how could you expect me to guess?
笨蛋，你在做什么？
You stupid jerk. What the fuck are you doing...
抢劫自己的房子？
robbing your own house?
混蛋！
You asshole!
你这个闷蛋自大的英国人
You stupid, stiff, pompous, English--
对不起
I'm sorry.
我的天！
God almighty!
怎会这样！
Bloody hell!
亲爱的！
Darling!
你有没有受伤？
Are you hurt?
跟我说话，你有没有受伤？
Speak to me. Are you hurt?
你不能说话吗？
Can't you speak?
发生什么事？
What has happened?
阿奇，我们被抢劫
Archie, we've been burgled.
- 不！ - 你有没有受伤？
- Oh, no! - Well, are you hurt?
我没事，只是有少许头痛
No, I'm fine. Bit of a headache.
我进来后有人打我的头 并把我绑起来
I came in here. Somebody hit me, tied me up with a--
我的天，这么晚了？
My God, is that the time?
什么事？
What?
- 我不知道原来这么晚了 - 什么？
- I didn't realize it was quite so late. - What?
- 我要出席会议 - 会议？
- I'm late for a conference. - A conference?
- 你刚被人袭击 - 我没事，我要去走了
- You've just been attacked! - It's nothing. I must fly. Sorry.
我回来后我帮你收拾房子 波席亚，你好
I'll help you tidy up when I get back. Hello, Portia.
发生什么事？
What's happened?
你父亲终于疯了
Your father has finally gone completely mental.
谢谢你
Thank you so much.
- 要香槟吗？ - 好
- Champagne? - Okay.
为我们干杯
To us.
我回家后，你猜是谁...
Well, I went back to the house and guess who--
我们做爱吧
Let's make love.
如果你坚持要的话，好吧
Well, if you absolutely insist.
- 不 - 什么？
- No. - What?
在地毯上
Here on the rug.
我很快回来，你先脱下衣服
I'll be right back. Get undressed.
有何不可？
Why not?
对
Why not indeed.
- 然后... - 怎样？
- Afterwards-- - Yeah?
我们一起去南美洲
Let's go to South America.
- 什么？ - 我们一起去南美洲
- What? - Let's fly to South America.
为什么要去南美洲？
Why South America?
那么冰岛吧
Okay, Iceland.
你究竟想要什么？
What do you really want out of life?
我不知道
I don't know.
我为什么那么喜欢你？
Why do I like you so much?
你会说意大利话吗？
Do you speak Italian?
我是意大利人
I am Italian!
但那是很难听的语言
But it's such an ugly language.
俄罗斯话怎样？
How about Russian?
- 你有钱吗？ - 我没钱的
- Are you rich? - No, I'm afraid not.
- 房子呢？ - 是属于温迪的，她很有钱
- What about the house? - That's Wendy's. She's the rich one.
- 你在做什么？ - 我或许会问你相同的问题
- What the hell are you doing? - I might ask you the same question.
你是谁？
Who are you?
- 什么？ - 穿回衣服
- What? - Get your clothes on.
- 请你立即离开好吗？ - 什么？
- Will you leave immediately, please? - What?
你来错地方
You're in the wrong flat.
这个公寓属于派崔克巴佛
This flat belongs to Patrick Balfour.
他去了香港，他借钥匙给我 请你离开！
He's in Hong Kong. He lent me the key. Now, get out!
但我们上周从管理员那租下这里
But we leased it from the agents last weekend.
那很明显的，那改变了一切
Yes, well, obviously that changes things a bit.
你不是阿奇利奇吗？
Aren't you Archie Leach?
什么？
What?
你买下我们在利斯顿的房子
You bought our house in Lissendon Gardens.
希娑和伊恩强森
Hazel and Ian Johnson.
真巧合
What a coincidence!
幸会
How nice to see you.
- 找谁？ - 万达，是阿奇
- Hello? - Wanda, it's Archie. Listen.
我不能再见你，我们完了 对不起
I can't see you anymore. I've got to end it. I'm sorry.
什么？
What?
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 好吗？ - 不要
- Okay. - Oh, no. Please.
- 我想道歉 - 我们已经分手，好吗？
- Look, I want to apologize. - I just finished it, all right?
等一下，你去哪里？
Okay, just-- Wait. Where are you going?
我们已分手，你不要再烦我
I just ended it, for Christ's sake! Will you leave me alone?
- 我们已分手，好吗？ - 等一下
- I've just ended it, all right? - Wait!
- 我只是想道歉 - 我们完了
- I just want to say I'm sorry. - It's all over!
- 我的天，救我 - 你冷静下来好吗？
-Jesus Christ! Someone help me! - Will you calm down?
求你相信我，不要再打我
Please, believe me. Don't beat me up again.
我今天很不高兴
I've had a terrible day.
- 你住口好吗？ - 天！不要杀我
- Will you shut up? -Jesus Christ! Don't kill me, please.
住口
Shut up then. Okay.
我只是想为了...
Look, I just wanna apologize...
我把你吊出窗户的事向你道歉
sincerely for when I dangled you out the window.
我真的很...我不应该那样做
I'm really, really-- Well, it was not a nice thing to do.
然后我在那里袭击你 我真的很...
And then when I attacked you in there, well, I'm really--
我怎知道你想抢劫自己的房子？
How could I know you were trying to rob your own house?
- 你只是想帮忙 - 是，谢谢
- I was just trying to help. - Yes. Thanks.
- 我想你相信我 - 那是我的错
- I wanted you to trust me. - Please, it was my fault.
- 你说得对 - 对
- That's true. - Yeah.
关于我的妹妹
Now, about my sister.
她很性感
She's a very sexy girl.
我明白你想和她发展
I understand you wanting to play around with her.
那没关系，我是错的
It's okay. I was wrong.
抱歉我妒忌，你去追求她吧
I'm sorry I was jealous. Just go ahead.
和她上床吧
Pork away, pal. Fuck her blue.
阿奇，我喜欢你，我只是想帮忙
I like you, Archie. I just wanna help.
天！
Oh, God!
我成功了
I did it.
我成功了 ！
I did it! Lovely!
难以置信
Unbe-fucking-lieveable!
汤玛森！
Thomason!
你做的很好
You've done well, my son.
计划是这样的
Now, here's the plan.
你去买四张今晚去里约热内卢的 头等机票
You get four tickets this evening for Rio, first class.
然后...
Then--
对，四张，稍后才摆脱奥图
Yeah, four. We get rid of Otto later.
然后回来公寓收拾行李
Then, back to the flat. Pack, collect me.
然后去卡思卡取珠宝
Then to the Cathcart Towers Hotel to pick up the jewels.
难以置信
Unbe-fucking-lievable!
很刺激，我不能相信
Oh, it's so exciting. I can't believe it.
他很安全
He's safe.
我快迟到了
Oh, I'm going to be late for court.
有人吗？奥图 ，你好
Hello? Oh, hello, Otto.
她刚离开了
No, she just left.
奥图 ，你欠我...
And, Otto, you owe me a--
什么？
What?
你欠我一镑
You owe me a pound.
不是祖母吧？
Not Granny?
遇上意外了
Met with an accident.
- 胡说！你在说谎！ - 说吧
- Bullshit! You're lying! - Come on.
死了？
Dead?
心脏病发
Heart attack.
我不相信
I don't believe this.
乔治今天下午就能离开
George'll be out this afternoon.
我们会去希思罗机场取赃货 然后...
We'll all go out to Heathrow, collect the loot, and then--
全部都是...
All thanks...
我的功劳
to me.
肯，赃货在机场吗？
So, the loot's at the airport, is it, Ken?
发生什么事？
What's happening?
肯...
Well, Ken...
我在吃薯条时要问你一些问题
I'm going to ask you some questions while I eat my chips.
第一题，哪个哲学家...
First, who is the philosopher...
在他的书中
who developed the concept of the ''superman''...
发展出 “超人” 的概念？
in Also sprach Zarathustra?
不知道？
No?
我要把马铃薯条塞进鼻子
That's a chip up the nose, I'm afraid.
是尼采，下一个问题
Friedrich Nietzsche. Next.
尼采在哪一本书中...
In which book did Nietzsche claim...
提出所有高级文化 都是以残酷为依据？
that almost all higher culture is based on cruelty?
你在思想还是又口吃？
Are you thinking, or are you in mid-stutter?
你是疯的
You're mad.
Beyond Good and Evil
Beyond Good and Evil.
我要问你一个简单的问题
I guess I'll have to ask you an easy one, huh?
好...
Okay, um--
让我想想
Let me think.
钻石在哪里？我给你一个线索
Where are the diamonds? I'll give you a clue.
在机场某个地方
Somewhere around the airport.
- 我不... - 不用急，还有很多时间
- I'm n-- - No hassle. There's plenty of time.
我会边吃着薯条一直到你告诉我
I'll just sit here and eat my chips until you tell me.
英国对美食的贡献就是薯条
The English contribution to world cuisine: the chip.
英国人会用什么跟 薯条一齐吃...
What do the English usually eat with chips...
而令它们好吃一点？
to make them more interesting?
等一下
Wait a moment!
是鱼吧？
It's fish, isn't it?
又一条
Here, boy. Down the hatch.
很美味
Delicious.
你...
You b--
最好吃绿色的？
Better eat the green one? Okay.
这个叫什么名字？
What's this one's name?
不是万达
Well, not Wanda, anyway.
我会叫她做午饭
I'm going to call her Lunch.
午饭，你好
Hello, Lunch.
避开绿色那一些
Avoid the green ones.
它们还没熟透
They're not ripe yet.
法医官在庭上发表证据时...
Now, you were in court, were you not, Inspector...
你在法庭上吗？
when the forensic evidence was read?
- 是 - 事实上...
- Yes, sir. - And the fact that...
汤玛森先生在之前的一个周末 安装窗户...
Mr. Thomason was installing windows the previous weekend...
引致玻璃碎片...
would account, would it not...
掉在他的裤子上吗？
for the presence of small particles of glass on his trousers?
警官，你不用急着回答
No hurry, Inspector. Please do take your time.
我很饱
I'm almost full.
- 差不多 - 停止
- Almost. - Stop!
不要
Please, don't.
万达，进食时间
Come on, Wanda. Gullet time.
机场附近的饭店名字是什么？
What are the names of those hotels that are right by the airport?
喜来登饭店？卡思卡饭店？...
What are they? The Airway Sheraton, The Post House, The Cathcart Towers--
卡思卡饭店？
The Cathcart Towers? Yes?
- 对 - 在保险箱里？
- Yes. - In a safe deposit box?
是
Yes.
- 什么？ - 钥匙在哪里？
- What? - Where's the key?
在鱼缸里
It's in the tank.
哪里？
Where?
- 在... - 珠宝箱里！
- In the t-- - Treasure chest!
哪里？
Where?
你...
You m-m--
谋杀
murdering--
我会杀死你
I'll kill you!
抱歉，肯，你的答案是错的
Sorry, Ken, but your answer was incorrect.
你真的认为它在里面吗？
Still, you really did think it was in there, didn't you?
什么？
What?
找谁？
Hello?
- 我知道钻石在哪里 - 在哪里？
- I know where the diamonds are. - Where?
钥匙在哪里？
Where's the key?
我有钥匙
I've got it.
你最快什么时候 能到达乔治的寓所？
How soon can you get to George's apartment?
你是住在伦敦梅利路...
You are Wanda Gershwitz of Kipling Mansions...
基普利公寓的万达格肖维吗？
Murray Road, London, West Nine?
- 是 - 请你告诉法庭...
- Yes. - Will you tell the court, please...
你怎样认识被告？
how do you know the defendant?
我们有两年亲密关系
We've had a relationship for two years.
亲密关系？
Relationship?
我们是恋人
We're lovers, your lord.
小姐，在今年三月四日早上
Miss Gershwitz, on the fourth of March of this year...
你在哪里？
in the morning, where were you?
我在梅利路的公寓里
I was at the apartment at Murray Road.
你独自一人 还是有别的人在场？
And were you by yourself or was there anyone else present?
还有别人
No, somebody else was there.
- 是谁？ - 我的哥哥
- Who was that? - My brother.
你的...
And did your--
你的哥哥？
Your brother?
我的哥哥
My brother.
是
Yes.
而你...
And--
你很肯定那是你的哥哥？
Are you quite sure it was your brother?
利奇先生，我肯定格肖维小姐 可以认得她的哥哥
Mr. Leach, I'm sure Miss Gershwitz can recognize her brother.
她认识了他一辈子
She's had a relationship with him all her life.
是，大人
Much obliged, my lord.
那个早上还有别的人在场吗？
Was there anyone else present that morning?
- 有，乔治也在场 - 谢谢你
- Yes, George was there. - Thank you.
- 但他在六点五十五分就离开 - 万达...
- But he left about five to 7:00. - Wanda.
我想知道...
I wonder--
利奇先生，什么事？
Yes, Mr. Leach?
我想知道...
I Wendy-- I Wanda-- I wonder--
你说六点五十五分
When you say five to 7:00, Miss Gershwitz...
你为什么那么肯定？
how can you be so sure?
因为我当时看过时钟
Oh, I looked at the clock, 'cause I was saying to myself...
我对我自己说他在六点五十五分 带着锯短的手枪去哪里？
''Where could he be going at five to 7:00 with that sawed-off shotgun?''
亲爱的！
Darling!
- 利奇， “亲爱的” ？ - 什么，甜心？
- Mr. Leach. ''Darling''? - Yes, dear?
你这个混蛋
You bitch! You fucking bitch!
制止那个人
Restrain that man.
- 制止这个人 - 混蛋！过来
- Restrain this man. - Come here, you bastard!
退庭，我现在把审讯押后
Clear the court. I'm adjourning this matter for now.
- 带犯人离开 - 退庭！
- Take the prisoner below. - Clear the court!
警员 ，拘捕那个人
Officers, arrest that man!
退庭
Clear the court!
可恶
Bloody hell!
我的丈夫被打伤
It's my husband. He's been hit.
你做得很好
You made it. Good. Bit of a knock, I'm afraid.
我从没试过那么受辱
I have never been so humiliated in my life.
我们的婚姻完蛋了
You can stick this marriage right in your bottom.
在法庭上见
I'll see you in court.
是
Yes.
就是这样
Well, that's it, then.
- 什么事？ - 我们要谈谈
- What? - We've got to talk.
你叫这些笨蛋走开
You tell those pigs to fuck off!
走开
Fuck off, pigs.
你们听到我说什么吗？走开
Did you hear what I said? Fuck off.
- 乔治，她怎样了？ - 你怎么了？
- What's she up to, George? - What are you up to?
你叫她“亲爱的”和 “万达”
You called her darling and Wanda.
我在帮她正确地说出证据
I've been helping her get her evidence straight.
- 一时冲口而出 - 你一直在教她？
- It slipped out. - You've been coaching her?
你认为怎样？我们有十分钟
What do you think? Look, we've got ten minutes.
他们会判你有罪吧？
They're gonna find you guilty, right?
如果你现在认罪 告诉他们赃货在哪里
If you plead guilty now, tell them where the loot is...
你或许只用判八年牢 五年半就能出狱
you may get away with eight years, out in five-and-a-half.
如果我供出奥图和万达又怎样？
What if I tell them about Otto and Wanda?
- 他们有份？ - 是
- They both did it? - Yeah.
很好，或许只判六年牢 四年就能出狱
Great. All right. Maybe six years, out in four.
钻石在哪里？
So where are the diamonds?
- 巴勒在哪里？ - 他在楼上
- Where's Bartlett? - Upstairs trying to calm things down.
它们在哪里？
So, where are they?
告诉巴勒，肯知道在哪里
Tell Bartlett Ken knows where they are.
如果你直接告诉我会方便一点
It'd be a lot quicker if you told me.
我会告诉巴勒，肯在哪里？
Okay, I'll tell Bartlett. Where's Ken?
他在公寓里
He's at the flat.
谢谢你的帮忙，我很快出来
Thank you for all your help. I'll be right out.
计程车！可恶
Taxi! Please! Shit.
- 来吧 - 什么？
- Come on. - What?
- 我们走吧 - 去哪里？
- Let's go. - Where?
- 布宜诺斯 - 什么？
- Buenos Aires. - What?
我们先去乔治的公寓，上车
We're going to George's flat first. Get in.
- 你有护照吗？ - 有
- Got your passport? - Yeah.
在我的手提包 看看我的护照在不在
Check the briefcase for mine.
趴下
Get your head down.
你抢劫珠宝商...
So you robbed the jewelers...
向警方供出你其中一个情人
turned one of your lovers over to the police...
叫另一个帮你找钻石
kept the other one on to help you find the diamonds...
当他在找的时候 你在法庭发假誓，对吗？
and when he does, you commit perjury in the High Court, right?
阿奇，在美国大家都是那样
Come on, Archie. Everybody does it in America.
在这个国家却不行
Well, not in this country, they don't!
对，英国人没说过谎 柴侄夫人没说过谎
Oh, right. Like nobody lies in England. Like Margaret Thatcher never lied.
我们相遇那一刻你已骗我
Look, you lied to me right from the moment we met.
- 你只是想和我上床 - 我爱上了你
- You just wanted to get me into bed. - I fell in love with you.
那么你为什么抛弃我？
How come you dumped me then?
因为我不够有钱，记得吗？
I wasn't rich enough, remember?
- 用俄罗斯话说话 - 不
- Say something in Russian. - No.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
我在想一个好原因...
I'm just trying to think of one good reason why...
我为什么要带你去南美洲
I should take you to South America with me.
这个怎样...
How about...
因为我有保险箱的钥匙
because I have the key to the safety deposit box.
那是一个好原因
That's a good reason.
- 奥图怎样？ - 我会处理他
- What do we do about Otto? - I'll handle Otto.
- 小心，他很危险的 - 我也是
- Be careful. He's dangerous. - So am I.
继续
Keep it running.
- 你为什么带他来？ - 奥图 ，等一下
- Why did you bring him? - Otto, just wait!
我开始认为你喜欢那个傻瓜
I'm beginning to think you like that fruit.
去拿钻石吧
Let's get the diamonds!
肯？
Ken?
你是肯吗？
Are you Ken?
你好吗？我是乔治的律师
How do you do? I'm George's barrister.
发生什么事？
What's happened?
- 我的天！ - 混蛋！
- Oh, my God! - Asshole!
你在想什么...
What the bloody hell do you think--
好吧
All right, then.
他们去了哪里？快点
Where have they gone? Quick.
什么？
What?
你有没有事？
Are you all right?
- 他们去了哪里？ - 他们去了卡思卡...
- Where have they gone? - They've gone to the Cathcart--
- 你病了吗？ - 不是...
- Are you ill? - No, no.
什么？
What?
你有口吃吗？
Have you got a stutter?
是
Yeah.
- 有一点 - 没关系
- A bit. - Okay, fine. Don't worry.
你知道他们去了哪里吗？
Do you know where they've gone?
好，哪里？
Fine. Where?
卡...饭店
The Ca-- Hotel.
饭店？哪一间饭店？
Hotel? Which hotel?
继续，没关系
Go on. It's okay.
好，慢着
All right. Wait.
慢慢说
Slowly. Very slowly.
不用急
No hurry.
说出来吧
Sing it.
还有很多时间
Plenty of time.
快点！对不起
Oh, come on! I'm sorry.
等一下
Wait.
写出来
Here, write it.
卡思卡饭店？
Cathcart Towers Hotel?
它在哪里？
Where is it?
写出来
Here, again.
希思罗机场
Heathrow Airport.
这是怎么回事？
Hey! What's the idea?
- 你不能留在那里 - 对不起
- You can't stay there. - Frightfully sorry.
拿去，是你的
Take it. It's yours.
谢谢 去里约热内卢的闸口在哪里？
Thank you so much. British Airways to Rio?
第四个闸口
Rio. Terminal four, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起，这是你的吗？
Excuse me, sir, is this your vehicle?
等一下，我很快回来
I'll be with you in a moment. I'll be right back.
走廊还是窗户旁？ 吸烟还是非吸烟？
Aisle or window? Smoking or non-smoking?
- 中间的是什么？ - 只要在非吸烟区，哪里都可以
- What was the middle one? - Anything in non-smoking is fine.
14号闸现在开始登机
Gate 1 4 is boarding now.
里约热内卢！
Rio!
不要向后看，后面有警察
Don't look back. There's a cop right behind us.
快点
Quick.
- 利奇先生，我们做到的 - 很好
- Yes, we can just do it, Mr. Leach. - Great.
行李？
Luggage?
不需要它们了
Don't really need any.
- 14号闸 - 谢谢
- Gate 1 4. - Thank you.
阿奇，快，接电话
Come on, Archie. Pick up the phone.
等一下，机场保安
Wait, sir. Airport Security.
- 可以看一看你的登机证吗？ - 好
- May I see your boarding pass, please? - Oh, yes, certainly.
请你过来这一边，好吗？
Very good. Now, would you mind stepping over here please?
- 你看，是女皇 - 哪里？
- Oh, look, the Queen. - Where?
不用紧张
Okay. Don't get excited.
是你，我担心了好一阵子
Oh, it's you. I was actually worried there for a minute.
- 举高双手 - 不！
- Keep your hands up. - No!
- 举高手 - 我跟你来个协议吧
- Put 'em up! - I'll make a deal with you.
- 我会举高一只 - 把另一只举高
- I'll put one up. - Put the other one up!
哪一个看来好一点？
Which looks better?
奥图 ，我警告你
I'm warning you, Otto.
你会怎样做？向我开枪？
What are you gonna do, shoot me?
像向狗开枪一样？
Gun me down in cold blood like a dog?
如果你想解决，何不和我决斗？
If you wanna settle something with me, then why don't you fight me?
你是男人吧？ 我们要像男人般决斗
You're a man, aren't you? Then let's fight like men. Come on!
好
All right.
- 好 - 好
- All right, then. - Okay.
- 阿奇，你看起来不错 - 对
- You look good, Arch. - That's right.
- 我以前在牛津打拳的 - 是吗？
- I used to box for Oxford. - Oh, yeah?
我以前为中央情报局杀人 举高双手
I used to kill for the CIA. Now, get your hands up.
你这个笨蛋
You spineless bimbo.
出去
Now, out.
我现在要向你开枪
I'm gonna have to shoot you now.
我在飞机起飞前有一点时间
But I've got a little time before my plane leaves...
我很想侮辱你
and I'm longing to humiliate you.
进去那个桶子里
So get in that barrel.
- 什么？ - 走进桶子里
- What? - In the barrel.
对
Right.
你们英国人自以为很优越？
You English. You think you're so superior, don't you?
你们是地球的垃圾
Well, you're the filth of the planet.
一班自大、没衣着品味...
A bunch of pompous, badly dressed...
穷困、性抑压的...
poverty-stricken, sexually repressed...
足球暴徒
football hooligans.
阿奇，再见
Good-bye, Archie.
至少我们不是那么低俗
Well, at least we're not irretrievably vulgar.
你知道你的问题所在吗？ 你不喜欢胜利者
You know your problem? You don't like winners.
- 胜利者？ - 对，胜利者
- Winners? - Yeah. Winners.
胜利者，像北越？
Winners, like North Vietnam?
住口
Shut up!
我们没有失去越南 那场战争平手
We did not lose Vietnam. It was a tie.
他们在那里打败你们
I'm telling ya, baby, they kicked your little ass there.
他们彻底打败你们
Boy, they whooped your hide real good.
- 他们没有 - 他们有
- No, they didn't. - Yes, they did.
<font  color="#4096d1">- 不，他们没有 - 是的，他们有
<font  color="#4096d1">不， 他们...
住口
Shut up!
- 阿奇，再见 - 你会开枪杀我吗？
- Good-bye, Archie. - You gonna shoot me?
我恐怕是，对不起
Yes, afraid so, old chap. Sorry.
奥图！
Look, Otto!
报仇
Revenge!
肯会来杀我
It's Ken coming to kill me.
肯，你怎样抓我？
How are you gonna catch me, Ken?
我在哪里？
Now, where was I? Oh, yeah.
糟了 ！
Shit! God--
可恶的水泥
Fucking limey cement.
慢着！
Wait!
肯尼，我可以叫你肯尼吗？
Kenny! May I call you Kenny?
- 记住万达！ - 我们有协议的
- Remember Wanda! - I've got the deal of a lifetime.
大家五五分帐，好吗？
Fifty-fifty. You and me. What do you say?
好，六四分帐
Okay, sixty-forty.
- 那是我最后的建议 - 报仇！
- That's my final offer. - Revenge!
我有个主意，你拿去全部
I've got an idea. You take it all. Yeah.
这是我的登机证
Here's my boarding pass.
我会...我会杀死你
I'm gonna-- I'm gonna kill you.
好，杀死我吧
Okay, fine. Come at me. Give me your best shot.
杀吧，你没有胆量的
Go on. You don't have the guts. Admit it.
你有胆量，等一下
Okay, you have the guts. Good. Wait.
死亡
Death.
对不起，我吃了你的鱼 好吗？
All right, I'm sorry I ate your fish, okay?
- 对不起 - 报仇！
- I'm sorry. - Revenge!
天，我说了对不起！
Jesus, I said I'm sorry! What the--
收拾他！
Got him!
收拾你，混蛋
Got you again, you bastard!
我的口吃消失了
Hey, I've lost my stutter. It's gone.
我能够说话
I can speak.
四牌楼有四辆四轮大马车
How much wood could a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could chuck wood?
你听着，两件事...
Now, listen, two things.
一，请你保持良好行为 否则我会勒死你
One: behave yourself from now on or I'll break your neck, okay?
二
Two:
戈尔巴乔夫，公开地...
Gorbachev, Glasnost--
莫洛托夫
Molotov.
- 俄式薄煎饼 - 列宁
- Blinis. - Lenin.
普希金
Pushkin.
- 基辅鸡 - 很好
- Chicken Kiev. - Good.
陀思妥也夫斯基
Dostoyevsky.
卢布
Rubles.
符拉迪沃斯托克
Vladivostok.
混蛋！
Asshole!
<font  color="#4096d1">阿奇和万达在里约热内卢结了婚 他们生了17个小孩
<font  color="#4096d1">和成立一个麻疯病院
<font  color="#4096d1">肯成为伦敦海洋世界的司仪
<font  color="#4096d1">奥图移居南非，成为司法部长